Guide to the Cynthia Macdonald Papers
University of Houston Libraries
- Writing
  - Poetry
    - Individual Poems
      - Thanksgiving in Cambridge, N.Y. (Box 7, Folder 78)
      - That Piece of Mine (Box 7, Folder 79)
      - That Will Be Done (Box 7, Folder 80)
      - Their Places Resolve and Dissolve (Box 7, Folder 81)
      - Theist Attack (Box 7, Folder 82)
      - Therein Hangs a Tale (Box 7, Folder 83)
      - They Simply Fade Away (Box 7, Folder 84)
      - The Thinnest of the Fat (Box 7, Folder 85)
      - This Die Is Straight and Colorfast (Box 7, Folder 86)
      - This Is the House That Jim Built (Box 7, Folder 87)
      - This Pair, That Pair: Despair (Box 7, Folder 88)
      - This Week’s Instructions Passed On (Box 7, Folder 89)
      - Those Who Live Alone (Box 7, Folder 90)
      - Thought Hat (Box 7, Folder 91)
      - Three (Box 7, Folder 92)
      - Three Begin Attempt to Sail Dhow Here from Kenya (N.Y. Times, May 11, 1967) (Box 7, Folder 93)
      - The Three Mouths (Box 7, Folder 94)
      - Three Ways of Making a Poem (Box 7, Folder 95)
      - Tip-it (Box 7, Folder 96)
      - Tit for Tat (Box 7, Folder 97)
      - To a Young Man in the Library (Box 7, Folder 98)
      - To Baudelaire, Debussy, and Basho (Box 7, Folder 99)
      - To My Husband (Box 7, Folder 100)
      - To Such Small Things Are We in Debt (Box 7, Folder 101)
      - To You I Would Speak (Box 7, Folder 102)
      - Today and To-morrow Series (Box 7, Folder 103)
      - Today I Celebrate by Crying (with Tears) (Box 7, Folder 104)
      - Today I Say (Box 7, Folder 105)
      - Tracking Connections (Box 7, Folder 106)
      - A Trained Diaphragm Can Help to Master Pain (Box 7, Folder 107)
      - Transfer (Box 7, Folder 108)
      - The Transformation of Water to Ice (Box 7, Folder 109)
      - Transgression (Box 7, Folder 110)
      - Transition from the Anglo Saxon (Box 7, Folder 111)
      - Trials (Box 7, Folder 112)
      - The Triborough Bridge a Crown for His Head (Box 7, Folder 113)
      - Trojan Women (Box 7, Folder 114)
      - Trout (Box 7, Folder 115)
      - Try to Find Out (Box 7, Folder 116)
      - Trying to Apprehend a Plot (Box 7, Folder 117)
      - Trying to Catch the Elusive Object (Box 7, Folder 118)
      - The Tune He Saw (Box 7, Folder 119)
      - Turning (Box 7, Folder 120)
      - TV Instructions as to What to Do for a Person Who Is Having a Heart Attack (Box 7, Folder 121)
      - Twice Too Long (Box 7, Folder 122)
      - The Twist (Box 7, Folder 123)
      - Two (Box 7, Folder 124)
      - Two Brothers in a Field of Absence (Box 7, Folder 125)
      - Two Faces (Box 7, Folder 126)
      - Two Sisters (Box 7, Folder 127)
      - Unbalanced Symmetries (Box 7, Folder 128)
      - Uncovering (Box 7, Folder 129)
      - Undertaking Solutions (Box 7, Folder 130)
      - An Unfair Poem (Box 7, Folder 131)
      - Unusual Cases (Box 7, Folder 132)
      - Vacation Rental with Outhouse (Box 7, Folder 133)
      - Vain Remedy (Box 7, Folder 134)
      - The Vale of Tears (Box 7, Folder 135)
      - Variations on a Stream (Box 7, Folder 136)
      - Vermeer’s Lady Reading at an Open Window (Box 7, Folder 137)
      - Versions of a City (Box 7, Folder 138)
      - Very Carefully (Box 7, Folder 139)
      - Victoria’s Secret (Box 7, Folder 140)
      - Villain (Box 7, Folder 141)
      - Villanelle (Box 7, Folder 142)
      - Visit to McGuire Air Force Base (Box 7, Folder 143)
      - Vocal Arpeggio (Box 7, Folder 144)
      - Volcano (Box 7, Folder 145)
      - Wait in the Chair (Box 7, Folder 146)
      - Waiting for an Ending (Box 7, Folder 147)
      - Waits and Measures (Box 7, Folder 148)
      - Walking through the Boxes (Box 7, Folder 149)
      - Walrus in the Central Park Zoo (Box 7, Folder 150)
      - Walt (Box 7, Folder 151)
      - Wanted: (Box 7, Folder 152)
      - War (Box 7, Folder 153)
      - Warsaw, September, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 154)
      - Watching the Gerbil Die (Box 7, Folder 155)
      - The Way Lives Go (Box 7, Folder 156)
      - We Are Blind-Sighted (Box 7, Folder 157)
      - The Wedding (Box 7, Folder 158)
      - Wedding Bans: January 1980 (Box 7, Folder 159)
      - Wedding Ring (Box 7, Folder 160)
      - Weeding out the Chickens (Box 7, Folder 161)
      - The Weekend: Fireworks – July 4, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 162)
      - The Weekend He Died (Box 7, Folder 163)
      - The Weight of Accumulated Sadness (Box 7, Folder 164)
      - Western Immigration (Box 7, Folder 165)
      - What Cannot Be Expressed (Box 7, Folder 166)
      - What Heat Signifies (Box 7, Folder 167)
      - What I Did on My Spring Vacation (Box 7, Folder 168)
      - What I Took Home on March 19 (Box 7, Folder 169)
      - What Is Missing on the 4th of July (Box 7, Folder 170)
      - What Is Never Lost (Box 7, Folder 171)
      - What No One Should Want to Have (Box 7, Folder 172)
      - What She Has Is Not Good Enough to Offer (Box 7, Folder 173)
      - What She Won’t Admit (Box 7, Folder 174)
      - What Went Wrong (Box 7, Folder 175)
      - When It's a Door (Box 7, Folder 176)
      - When the Bough Breaks (Box 7, Folder 177)
      - The Whether of One Evening (Box 7, Folder 178)
      - Who Is Chicken? (Box 7, Folder 179)
      - Why I Hate Poetry (Box 7, Folder 180)
      - Why Penelope Was Happy (Box 7, Folder 181)
      - Widow's Work (Box 7, Folder 182)
      - The Will Not Tell Overture (Box 7, Folder 183)
      - William Gass and the Singing Contest at Pantheon Publishing (Box 7, Folder 184)
      - Winter in Houston (Box 7, Folder 185)
      - Winter in the Arctic (Box 7, Folder 186)
      - Winter Letter/Shell Sekiyu (Box 7, Folder 187)
      - Winter Repast in the Blizzard of ‘78 (Box 7, Folder 188)
      - The Witches Auction (Box 7, Folder 189)
      - Wives (Box 7, Folder 190)
      - A Woman, Almost Seventy Reads the Day’s Obituaries (Box 7, Folder 191)
      - WONC, Inc (Box 7, Folder 192)
      - Words Thought but Never Said (Box 7, Folder 193)
      - A Work of Art (Box 7, Folder 194)
      - The World’s Fattest Dancer (Box 7, Folder 195)
      - Worn Out (Box 7, Folder 196)
      - Yields and Measures (Box 7, Folder 197)
      - The You Addressed (Box 7, Folder 198)
      - You Slice a Tomato (Box 7, Folder 199)
      - Various (multiple poems per page or multiple poems clipped together) (Box 7, Folder 200)
    - Poetry Fragments and Untitled Poems
      Both typed and handwritten, fragments and untitled poems appear on everything from full sheets of paper to bits of scrap paper.
      - Poetry fragments and untitled poems (Box 8, Folder 1-17)
    - Poetry Ideas and Research
      Cynthia Macdonald jotted down ideas and collected news clippings and other printed materials for ideas and research for her poems.
      - Decoys – Poem & Title (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - Big Thicket Poem (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - Mary Cassat – 1 (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - Mary Cassat – 2 (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - Plumbing Stuff (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Poetry Family Tree Project (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Traveling up the Nile (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Volcano poem (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Notes (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Clippings and printed material (Box 9, Folder 6-10)
  - Fiction
    Fiction includes short stories, both published and unpublished, as well as portions of novels that Cynthia Macdonald began writing. Material also includes notes and clippings for fiction ideas and research.
    - Short story: “A Certain Grace” (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Short story: “The Fat Woman” (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Stories and ideas (Box 9, Folder 13-15)
    - Ideas, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Idea: Children’s book (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Idea: The Disgusting Book for Children (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Idea: “Memorial Service” (Papp story) (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Ideas for novels (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Idea: Bon Ton (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Idea: Eastern Europe (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Idea: Train novel (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Novel: Kidnapped (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Novel: Schumann (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Turandot: assorted notes and clippings (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
    - Turandot: printed material for research (Box 10, Folder 3-5)
  - Nonfiction
    Cynthia Macdonald’s nonfiction work includes essays; book reviews; written introductions of other writers for events such as poetry readings; and written copies of talks given. Material also includes notes and clippings for ideas and research related to nonfiction writing.
    - Amy Lowell, Poetry Society of America (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Drafts of Barcelona prose (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Essay for Alberta Turner’s Poets Teaching (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Essay on sports poem for POETSPEAK (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Essay: The April Case (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
    - Essay: Deaths of Beautiful Ladies (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Essay: The Hand, Harper’s Bazaar (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Essay: Hats (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Essay: “Heaven Is God’s Throne; Earth, His Footstool” (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Essay: “How to Know Where to Go” (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Essay: The Neck, NY Times (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Essay: Notebook (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Essay: The Role of the Stars in Psychoanalysis (Box 10, Folder 19-20)
    - Essay: Wallace Stevens (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Essay on the creative process (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Essays (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Essay ideas (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Review: Listening to Prozac (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Review: Secrets of the Soul, Houston Chronicle (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Reviews and written introductions of other writers (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Talk: All Purpose Ending (Folger) (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Talk: Brearley 50th Reunion (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Talk: Dickinson (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Talk: Farfel Award recipient speech (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Talk: Houston and the Artist (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Talk: How to Read Poetry (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Talk: Jane Cooper’s 70th birthday (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Talk: Maps and Mirrors for CAM (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Talk: Marguerite Ross Barnett (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Talk: Marilyn Monroe/C.A.M. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Talk: Oshman’s (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Talk: Teaching Poetry (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Talk: U.H. H&A graduation (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Talk: U.H. Library (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Talk: Walt Whitman (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Talk: W.B. Yeats (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Writer in the City (Berlin) (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Autobiography
    The Autobiography subseries features notes, snippets, ideas, clippings, and mementos, as collected and organized by Cynthia Macdonald.
    - Notes, clippings, ideas (Box 11, Folder 18-20)
    - March 1993 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - June 1993 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Journals, Diaries, and Dreams
    This subseries comprises Cynthia Macdonald’s personal journals and diaries, as well as written recollections of dreams.
    - Journals, diaries, dreams (Box 11, Folder 23-25)
    - Journals, diaries, dreams: Myron Simon (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Journals, diaries, dreams: William Cantrell (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Psychoanalysis
    Cynthia Macdonald’s psychoanalysis-related writings include papers and presentations, as well as notes collected for these writings.
    - A House Divided: Interviews; J. Robinson contributions (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - A House Divided: James Robinson intro (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - A House Divided: poem versions (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - A House Divided (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - A House Divided addendum (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - A House Divided: complete (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - A House Divided: early version (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Writing Blocks (Box 12, Folder 5-6)
    - Daily Cougar/Writer’s Block (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Brief writings (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Collaborative paper written by CLM and Steve [Sonn.] (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Other Writings
    This subseries includes a translation of Dante’s Divine Comedy; notes and printed material related to that translation; ideas for various writing projects; an opera libretto, opera ideas, and reviews of operas; scripts and ideas for plays, movies, and television shows; notes on index cards; and assorted ideas, notes, and clippings for unnamed writing projects.
    - Dante translation: Canto VII (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Dante translation: Canto VIII (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Dante translation: Canto VIII notes (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Dante translation: Canto LXXXI (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Dante translation: Dante business (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Dante translation: Dante final (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Dante translation: Dante memorabilia (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Dante translation: Dante notes (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Dante translation: Divine Comedy (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Ideas: baby book (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Ideas: book titles (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Ideas: Dodo/animal project notes (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Ideas: Percy Grainger (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Ideas: Rosellen, Marv, CM teaching book (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Ideas: Why Anna Freud Never Married (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - In a Word contribution (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Opera libretto and ideas (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Opera review: Mozart’s The Magic Flute (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Opera review: Street Scene (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Opera reviews and notes (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Play ideas and movie ideas (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Notes on index cards (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Script: “The Murderer’s Daughter” (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Teleplay idea: Beerbohm/Woolf play for Channel 8 Writers Project (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Teleplays/scripts for CBC Vancouver re: Japan 1965 (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Teleplays/scripts for Channel 8 Writers Project (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Uncategorized ideas, notes, and clippings (Box 12, Folder 36)
- Correspondence
  The Correspondence series is especially rich, featuring letters and postcards to and from Cynthia Macdonald’s writing friends, colleagues, and family members. The series is divided into four sub-series: Incoming; Outgoing; Writing Submissions and Solicitations; and Third-Party Correspondence. Further description of each sub-series is provided in the corresponding section below.
  - Incoming Correspondence
    Incoming correspondence is arranged alphabetically by the last names of the senders. The last four folders of the sub-series contain correspondence identified by the senders’ first names only and correspondence from unknown senders. Among the family and friends sending letters to Cynthia Macdonald are many noteworthy writers and artists, including: Roger Angell; John Ashbery; Charles Baxter; John Barth; Marion Barthelme; Gay Block; Rita Mae Brown; Alan Cheuse; Judy Collins; Jane Cooper; Robert Coover; Peter DeVries; James Dickey; Mark Doty; Rita Dove; Rackstraw Downes; Rikki Ducornet; Alan Dugan; Stephen Dunn; Judy Dworkin; Stuart Dybeck; Louise Erdrich; Jules Feiffer; Carolyn Forche; Siv Cedering Fox; Helen Frankenthaler; Tess Gallagher; James Gleick; Vivian Gornick; Donald Hall; Barbara Hamby; Brenda Hillman; Edward Hirsch; Maureen Howard; Richard Howard; Donald Justice; Barbara Kellerman; Carolyn Kizer; Maxine Kumin; Philip Levine; Audre Lorde; Beverly Lowry; Thomas Lux; Frances Mayes; James Michener; Vassar Miller; Simon Moss; Carol Muske; Hans Namuth; Howard Norman; Kathleen Norris; Cynthia Ozick; Molly Peacock; Robert Peters; Marge Piercy; Stanley Plumly; Adrienne Rich; Joanna Russ; William Safire; Grace Schulman; Anne Sexton; Tom Sleigh; Nicholas Spice; Daniel Stern; Gail Storey; James Surls; May Swenson; Anne Truitt; Alberta Turner; Chase Twitchell; Mona Van Duyn; Sidney Wade; Diane Wakoski; Nancy Willard; Charles Wright; Marguerite Young; and Adam Zagajewski.
    - A (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Ba (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Be – Bloch (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Block, Gay (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Blu – Bri (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Brock-Broido, Lucie (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Brouwer – Bru (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Bryan, Sharon (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Bu – By (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Cantrell, William “Bill” (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Car – Collier (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Collins, Judy (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Cook – Coolidge (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Cooper, Jane (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Cooper, R.C. – Cu (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Da – Der (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - DeSchweinitz, George (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Dev – Dre (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Driskell, Leon (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Dru – Dy (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - E (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Fa – Fle (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Fli – Forche (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Ford, Harry (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Fortney – France (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Frankenthaler, Helen (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Fras – Ful (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Furman, Laura (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Ga (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Gallaher, Eddie (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Gee, Judy (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Gel – Gu (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Ha (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Hea – Herrmann, John, Jr. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Herrmann, Marjorie “Marty” (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Herz – Hirst, Donald (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Hirst, Dorothy Kiam Lee (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Hirt – Howard, Maureen (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Howard, Richard (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Howe – Hu (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - I – J (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Ka (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Kellerman, Barbara (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Kelman – Ki (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Kn – Ku (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - La – Led (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Lee, Leonard (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Lee, Miranda – Lor (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Lowry, Beverly (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Lu – Ly (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - MacArthur – Macdonald, Dwight (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Macdonald, E.C. “Mac” (Box 14, Folder 24-26)
    - Macdonald, E.C. “Mac” (2 of 3) (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Macdonald, E.C. “Mac” (3 of 3) (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Macdonald, H.C. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Macdonald, Jennifer “Timmie” (Box 15, Folder 2-3)
    - Macdonald, Jennifer “Timmie” (2 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Macdonald, Scott (1 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Macdonald, Scott (2 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Macdonald, Susan Ada (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Mag – Maz (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Mc (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Me – Miller, C. (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Miller, Leslie (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Miller, Lynn and Lynda (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Miller, V. – Moss, H. (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Moss, Simon (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Mou – My (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Namuth, Hans (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Nay – Nu (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Oa – Olsen (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Olsson, Peter (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Op – Oz (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Pa – Pea (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Pei – Pet (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Ph – Pr (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Quinn, Alexandra (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Quinn, Alice (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Quinn, Carol (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Ra – Rice (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Rich, Adrienne (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Rif – Rosenwasser (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Rossabi (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Rosser – Ry (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Sa (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Sc (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Se (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Sh (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Si – Simon, H. (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Simon, Myron (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Sip – Sl (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Sm – Spe (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Spice, Nicholas (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Spitz – Sti (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Sto – Str (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Su – Sy (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Ta – Thompson, E. (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Thompson, Jim (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Thompson, T. – Tri (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Tro – Tw (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - U (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - V (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Wa (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - We – Wi (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Wo – Wr (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Y (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Zagajewski, Adam (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Zamora, Lois (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Ze – Zw (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - First names only and unknown senders (Box 16, Folder 26-29)
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    Cynthia Macdonald’s outgoing correspondence is arranged chronologically.
    - 1930 – 1939 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - 1940 – 1949 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - 1950 – 1959 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - 1960 – 1964 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - 1965 – 1969 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - 1970 – 1973 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - 1974 – 1975 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - 1976 – 1979 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - 1980 – 1986 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - 1987 – 1989 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - 1990 – 1994 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - 1995 – 1996 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - 1997 – 1999 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - 2000 – 2004 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Unknown dates (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Writing Submission and Solicitation Correspondence
    This sub-series includes correspondence between Cynthia Macdonald and the editors at magazines and literary journals regarding writing submissions and solicitations to submit her writing. Folders contain attachments and enclosures that were originally included with the correspondence. Some of Macdonald’s original folders are also included, in the cases in which she wrote notes, names, and addresses of editors on the folders themselves. The files are arranged alphabetically by the names of the magazines, journals, and anthologies.
    - The American Poetry Review (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - The American Review (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - American Sports Poems (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - The American Voice (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Antaeus (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Appetite: Food as a Metaphor (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Ardis Anthology of New American Poetry (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Articulations (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - The Atlantic Monthly (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Borderlands (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - The Bridge (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - The Canadian Forum (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Choomia (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - The Connecticut Poetry Review (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - CutBank (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Dominion Review (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Esquire (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Evergreen (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Feminist Studies (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Field (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - A Geography of Poets (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Global City Review (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Grand Street (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Gravida (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - The Hampden-Sydney Poetry Review (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - The Herman Review (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Hippocrates (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - The Iowa Review (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Limestone (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Many Mountains Moving (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - The Massachusetts Review (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Michigan Quarterly Review (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - Mid-American Review (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - The Minnesota Review (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - The Missouri Review (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - MoonRabbit Review (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - Mosaic (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - Ms. Magazine (Box 18, Folder 38)
    - The Nation (Box 18, Folder 39)
    - New Directions Annual (Box 18, Folder 40)
    - New Letters (Box 18, Folder 41)
    - The New Republic (Box 18, Folder 42)
    - New Virginia Review (Box 18, Folder 43)
    - New Writings on Motherhood and Poetics (Box 18, Folder 44)
    - New York Quarterly (Box 18, Folder 45)
    - New York State Artists in Exhibition (NYSAE) (Box 18, Folder 46)
    - The New York Times (Box 18, Folder 47)
    - The New Yorker (Box 18, Folder 48)
    - Open Places (Box 18, Folder 49)
    - The Paris Review (Box 18, Folder 50)
    - Parnassus (Box 18, Folder 51)
    - Partisan Review (Box 18, Folder 52)
    - Pearl (Box 18, Folder 53)
    - Ploughshares (Box 18, Folder 54)
    - Poetry Magazine (Box 18, Folder 55)
    - The Poetry Miscellany (Box 18, Folder 56)
    - Poetry Northwest (Box 18, Folder 57)
    - POETSPEAK (Box 18, Folder 58)
    - Prairie Schooner (Box 18, Folder 59)
    - Prism (Box 18, Folder 60)